1stopmom.com 2018-12-07

# 1StopMom - Privacy Policy | 1StopMom

This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices for 1StopMom. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by this web site. It will notify you of the following:

  * What personally identifiable information is collected from you through the web site, how it is used and with whom it may be shared.
  * What choices are available to you regarding the use of your data.
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.
  * How to reach us if you have any questions or concerns

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Cookies

We use “cookies” on this site. A cookie is a piece of data stored on a site visitor’s hard drive to help us improve your access to our site and identify repeat visitors to our site. For instance, when we use a cookie to identify you, you would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information on our site.

Some of our business partners may use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, links, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics gain insights and improve the functionality of 1StopMom. The information collected includes the content you view, the date and time you visit 1StopMom, and the location associated with your IP address. We may share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. You can opt out of allowing Google to use cookies by visiting [Google’s Ads Settings page](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) . You can opt out of allowing other third-party vendors to use cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative Opt-Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

## Who we share your data with

1StopMom is the only owner of information collected on this site. We only have access to/collect information that you voluntarily give us via email or other direct contact from you. We _**will not**_ sell or give this information to anyone.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## What we do with you data

We will use your information to respond to you, regarding the reason you contacted us. We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, other than as necessary to fulfill your request or to ship a prize that you have won through one of giveaways.

Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via email if you subscribe to or newsletter in the future to tell you about new posts here on 1StopMom or changes to this privacy policy.

## Security

We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline.

Wherever we collect sensitive information, that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser, or looking for “https” at the beginning of the address of the web page.

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

## Giveaways

1StopMom may request information like your name, email address and social media links through giveaways that we host. Participation in these giveaways is completely voluntary. You may choose whether or not to participate and therefore disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information such as your name and mailing address. Contact information will only be used to notify the winners and ship prizes.

If you have any questions or concerns feel free to send me an email at onestopmom@gmail.com

_**Updated May 23, 2018**_
